Dorothy Thompson Papers
Dorothy Thompson Papers
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dorothy Thompson.
Inventory
- Incoming correspondence
  - A - General correspondence
    - Abe-Ame, 16 May 1933-11 May 1959; 106 items (Box 1)
    - Ame-Aut, 11 Nov 1932-12 Mar 1958; 65 items (Box 1)
    - Acheson, Dean, 21 Sep 1945; 06 Apr 1949; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Adams, Franklin and Esther, 03 Dec 1930-09 Mar 1959; 9 items (Box 1)
    - Allen, Jay, 24 Oct 1938-27 Aug 1946; 11 items (Box 1)
    - Alsop, Joseph and Stewart, 18 Feb 1948-15 Jun 1960; 8 items (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, The, 20 Nov 1950-08 Nov 1951; 10 items (Box 1)
    - American Council for Judaism
      - 20 May 1941-06 Jun 1950, 110 items (Box 1)
      - 19 Feb 1951-28 Oct 1958, 68 items (Box 1)
    - American Express Company, The, 28 Feb 1951-11 May 1951; 5 items (Box 1)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 27 Feb 1939-08 Aug 1958; 11 items (Box 1)
    - American Middle East Relief, Inc., 20 Jul 1950-28 Feb 1957; 17 items (Box 1)
    - American University of Beirut, 10 Jan 1951-26 Mar 1952; 4 items (Box 1)
    - American Way, Inc., The, 18 Aug 1953-04 Nov 1953; 4 items (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Henry, 01 Aug 1934-23 Apr 1960; 26 items (Box 2)
    - Apartment Locating Bureau, 07 Aug 1958-16 Sep 1958; 3 items (Box 2)
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 07 Dec 1938-21 Dec 1959; 9 items (Box 2)
    - Arthur, Franchon M., 20 Nov 1944-22 Jan 1945; 3 items (Box 2)
    - Ascoli, Max, Mr. and Mrs., 20 Jun 1934-13 Nov 1944; 18 items (Box 2)
    - Astor, Nancy, 01 Dec 1949; 23 Sep 1955; 3 items (Box 2)
    - Atlantic Monthly, The, 28 Aug 1928-06 Oct 1960; 11 items (Box 2)
    - Atwater, Mrs. W. Clarke, 04 Nov 1960; 7 items (Box 2)
    - Author's League of America, Inc., The, 05 Mar 1958; 3 items (Box 2)
  - American Friends of the Middle East
    - 12 Jan 1951-21 May 1951, 23 items (Box 2)
    - 04 Jun 1951-31 Jul 1951, 23 items (Box 2)
    - 01 Aug 1951-28 Sep 1951, 28 items (Box 2)
    - 04 Oct 1951-29 Dec 1951, 25 items (Box 2)
    - 09 Jan 1950-19 Dec 1951, William Eddy; 26 items (Box 2)
    - 01 Jun 1951-13 Sep 1951, 15 items; Cornelius Van H. Engert (Box 2)
    - 02 Jan 1952-29 Jun 1952, 44 items (Box 2)
    - 02 Jul 1952-24 Sep 1952, 26 items (Box 2)
    - 01 Oct 1952-30 Dec 1952, 18 items (Box 2)
    - 10 Apr 1952-27 Oct 1952, Garland Evans Hopkins; 12 items (Box 2)
    - 06 Jan 1953-28 Mar 1953, 26 items (Box 2)
    - 01 Apr 1953-29 May 1953, 28 items (Box 2)
    - 02 Jun 1953-30 Sep 1953, 50 items (Box 3)
    - 02 Oct 1953-31 Dec 1953, 27 items (Box 3)
    - 23 Jan 1953-18 Mar 1953, Garland Evans Hopkins; 5 items (Box 3)
    - 01 Jan 1954-19 Mar 1954, 27 items (Box 3)
    - 16 Apr 1954-28 Aug 1954, 37 items (Box 3)
    - 04 Sep 1954-20 Dec 1954, 28 items (Box 3)
    - 12 Jan 1954-06 Oct 1954, Garland Evans Hopkins; 17 items (Box 3)
    - 21 Mar 1954-20 Sep 1954, Kay Sisto; 10 items (Box 3)
    - 08 Jan 1955-27 Mar 1955, 18 items (Box 3)
    - 04 Apr 1955-29 Jun 1955, 14 items (Box 3)
    - 16 Aug 1955-06 Dec 1955, 15 items (Box 3)
    - 09 Feb 1955-19 Sep 1955, William Z. Cline; 11 items (Box 3)
    - 29 Mar 1955-07 Oct 1955, William Archer Wright; 13 items (Box 3)
    - 04 Jan 1956-27 Feb 1956, 11 items (Box 3)
    - 05 Mar 1956-26 Jun 1956, 24 items (Box 3)
    - 06 Jul 1956-19 Oct 1956, 18 items (Box 3)
    - 05 Nov 1956-27 Dec 1956, 21 items (Box 3)
    - 13 Jan 1956-11 Oct 1956, William Z. Cline; 9 items (Box 4)
    - 11 Jan 1956-28 Jun 1956, William Archer Wright; 10 items (Box 4)
    - 03 Jan 1957-25 Mar 1957, 28 items (Box 4)
    - 02 Apr 1957-10 Jun 1957, 18 items (Box 4)
    - 12 Jul 1957-18 Dec 1957, 16 items (Box 4)
    - 18 Jan 1958-29 Dec 1958, 12 items (Box 4)
    - 06 Feb 1958-09 May 1958, William Z. Cline; 5 items (Box 4)
    - 03 Mar 1958-30 Jun 1958, Garland Evans Hopkins; 7 items (Box 4)
    - 10 Feb 1959, 24 Nov 1959, 3 items (Box 4)
    - 15 Jan 1960-03 Dec 1960, 6 items (Box 4)
    - Organizational material, 3 folders, 78 items (Box 4)
  - B - General correspondence
    - Bab-Bel, 16 Jul 1931-28 Apr 1958; 75 items (Box 4)
    - Bel-Ble, 20 Oct 1930-23 Apr 1956; 58 items (Box 4)
    - Bli-Bos, 05 Feb 1949-03 Jan 1960; 46 items (Box 5)
    - Bou-Bre, 01 Oct 1937-09 Dec 1960; 26 items (Box 5)
    - Bri-Byr, 06 Nov 1940-11 Mar 1955; 71 items (Box 5)
    - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 01 Oct 1950-23 May 1958; 19 items (Box 5)
    - Barr, Springfellow, 08 Nov 1944-31 Mar 1958; 4 items (Box 5)
    - Barrie, J. M., 13 May 1930; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 13 Nov 1944-16 Jun 1959; 3 items (Box 5)
    - Beals and Nicholson, 08 Jan 1951-05 Feb 1951; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Beaverbrook, William Maxwell Aitken, 25 May 1923; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Bell, Canon Bernard Iddings, 14 Jul 1950-01 Jan 1952; 6 items (Box 5)
    - Bell, Ralph and Marjorie, 04 Jun 1951-08 Jun 1953; 7 items (Box 5)
    - Bell Syndicate
      - 04 Apr 1941- 02 Dec 1948, John N. Wheeler; 87 items (Box 5)
      - 01 Feb 1949-24 Dec 1953, John N. Wheeler; 154 items (Box 5)
      - 28 Jan 1954-12 Apr 1960, John N. Wheeler; 95 items (Box 6)
    - Berger, Elmer, 03 Jul 1951-28 Oct 1958; 3 items (Box 6)
    - Biddle, Francis, 06 Apr 1943; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Blesch, Josephine, 23 Dec 1953-20 Dec 1959; 12 items (Box 6)
    - Boeker, Alexander, 03 Feb 1948-22 Jul 1953; 8 items (Box 6)
    - Borah, William E., 07 Dec 1929; 1 item (Box 6)
    - Borchardt, Hermann, 08 Apr 1947-17 Sep 1947; 8 items (Box 6)
    - Bottome, Phyllis, 25 Jul 1928-23 Oct 1958; 21 items (Box 6)
    - Bouton, S. Miles, 19 Jan 1949-29 Nov 1959; 22 items (Box 6)
    - Boveri, Margaret, 28 Feb 1952-20 Jan 1961; 18 items (Box 6)
    - Boxer, John, 20 Apr 1948-30 Jun 1948; 6 items (Box 6)
    - Brandt, Karl and Anita, 02 Aug 1938-26 May 1959; 41 items (Box 6)
    - Buck, Pearl S., 03 Dec 1942-02 Aug 1952; 5 items (Box 6)
    - Buhlig, Richard, 02 Jan 1932-10 May 1952; 21 items (Box 6)
    - Byrd, Richard E., 21 Aug 1950-04 Jan 1951; 3 items (Box 6)
  - C - General correspondence
    - Cad-Cer, 05 Aug 1931-18 Feb 1960; 66 items (Box 6)
    - Cha-Col, 03 Feb 1939-11 Nov 1957; 134 items (Box 6)
    - Com-Czu, 04 Nov 1931-19 May 1960; 109 items (Box 7)
    - Cabell, James Branch, 30 Aug 1930-06 Nov 1930; 2 items (Box 7)
    - Canfield, Cass, 18 Feb 1949-10 Feb 1959; 13 items (Box 7)
    - C. A. R. E., 07 Feb 1947-17 Jul 1952; 20 items (Box 7)
    - Carter Insurance, 31 Jul 1947-05 Jan 1960; 69 items (Box 7)
    - Casanova, Grace, 09 Jun 1939-30 Aug 1960; 31 items (Box 7)
    - Cerf, Bennett, 06 Apr 1943; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Churchill, Winston, 16 Feb 1944-03 Jan 1958; 10 items (Box 7)
    - Clark, Madelaine, 15 Oct 1941-04 Feb 1943; 16 items (Box 7)
    - Clark, Wesley, 01 Aug 1951-01 Nov 1960; 22 items (Box 7)
    - Clay, Lucius, 07 Jan 1948-24 Jan 1949; 4 items (Box 7)
    - Cocteau, Jean, 15 Jun 1945; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Committees, 05 Jan 1946-20 Dec 1960; 76 items (Box 7)
    - Common Cause, 31 Mar 1948-14 Apr 1951; 38 items (Box 7)
    - Condolences re: death of Maxim Kopf
      - Jul 1958, A-D; 73 items (Box 8)
      - Jul 1958, E-O; 120 items (Box 8)
      - Jul 1958, P-Z; 100 items (Box 8)
      - Jul 1958, Unidentifiable; 37 items (Box 8)
    - Connally, Thomas, 13 Apr 1950; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Costain, Thomas B., 01 Jul 1931-17 Jul 1931; 2 items (Box 8)
    - Cousins, Norman, 27 Nov 1959; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Crosser, Paul, 28 Apr 1953-21 Oct 1955; 7 items (Box 8)
    - Crusade for Freedom, 27 Dec 1950-16 Dec 1952; 8 items (Box 8)
    - Culbertson, Ely and Dorothy, 23 Jun 1944-24 Sep 1957; 43 items (Box 8)
  - D - General correspondence
    - Dai-Def, 14 Jul 1928-30 Jun 1960; 55 items (Box 8)
    - Dei-Due, 07 Jul 1940-29 Jul 1955; 67 items (Box 8)
    - Duk-Dyn, 02 Aug 1949-10 Jan 1958; 22 items (Box 9)
    - Dahlquist, John E., 02 Feb 1950; 02 Aug 1954; 3 items (Box 9)
    - Dana, Harold S., 25 Apr 1950-28 Mar 1960; 50 items (Box 9)
    - Daniel, Anita, 21 Oct 1930-09 Apr 1960; 12 items (Box 9)
    - Davis, Elmer, 03 Sep 1942-15 Feb 1944; 2 items (Box 9)
    - Debs, Eugene V., 13 May 1926; 1 item (Box 9)
    - De Conti, Marc C., 07 Mar 1950-17 Mar 1951; 3 items (Box 9)
    - De Gasperi, Alcide, 06 Aug 1946; 1 item (Box 9)
    - De Gaulle, Charles, 10 Apr 1948; 1 item (Box 9)
    - De Groot, Roy, 02 Jul 1950-28 Mar 1951; 6 items (Box 9)
    - Deichmann, Hans, 15 Dec 1943-19 Jun 1957; 37 items (Box 9)
    - De Sales, Reine, 30 Aug 1937-14 Jul 1952; 13 items (Box 9)
    - Detmold, Mabel, 25 Jul 1947-20 Sep 1957; 12 items (Box 9)
    - De Voto, Bernard, 11 Dec 1942; 21 Nov 1943; 2 items (Box 9)
    - Dewey, Thomas E., 14 Apr 1939; 22 Mar 1944; 2 items (Box 9)
    - Dorfmann, Ania, 11 Sep 1949; undated; 17 items (Box 9)
    - Drawbell, James, 12 Jan 1944-21 Oct 1954; 21 items (Box 9)
    - Drucker, Peter, 21 Feb 1950-23 Nov 1957; 6 items (Box 9)
    - Dudensing, Patrick, 17 Feb 1949-28 Aug 1956; 74 items (Box 9)
    - Dulles, Allen W., 28 Jan 1948-08 Feb 1950; 4 items (Box 9)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 30 Oct 1953; 04 Jan 1954; 2 items (Box 9)
  - E - General correspondence
    - Eat-Ehr, 23 Jul 1931-21 Oct 1960; 25 items (Box 9)
    - Eic-Eye, 28 Apr 1930-04 Jan 1956; 46 items (Box 9)
    - Eastland, James, 22 Oct 1958; 1 item (Box 9)
    - Eaton, Cyrus, 10 Apr 1944-22 Apr 1959; 9 items (Box 9)
    - Eddy, William, 06 May 1959-04 Feb 1960; 4 items (Box 9)
    - Editorial Exchange, 06 Jul 1949-01 Sep 1954; 11 items (Box 9)
    - Elliman, Douglas E., 01 Aug 1957-14 Jun 1960; 9 items (Box 9)
    - Ely, Henrietta and Gertrude, Feb 30, 1943-18 Apr 1956; 10 items (Box 9)
    - Emmet, Christopher, 13 Oct 1948-17 Nov 1950; 8 items (Box 10)
    - Empire Travel Service, 26 Oct 1949-24 Nov 1953; 17 items (Box 10)
    - Ernst, Morris L., 09 Mar 1932-06 Dec 1960; 12 items (Box 10)
    - Evans, Ernestine, 06 Aug 1934-06 Dec 1960; undated; 46 items (Box 10)
    - Washington Evening Star, 27 Sep 1952-16 Jan 1957; 10 items (Box 10)
  - F - General correspondence
    - Fab-Fie, 29 Aug 1928-15 Dec 1960; 42 items (Box 10)
    - Fif-Fre, 19 Dec 1930-05 Mar 1959; 75 items (Box 10)
    - Fri-Fur, 01 Jan 1939-06 Nov 1957; 36 items (Box 10)
    - Fadiman, Clifton, 17 Apr 1944-10 Aug 1944; 6 items (Box 10)
    - Farley, James A., 02 Nov 1939-18 Feb 1956; 3 items (Box 10)
    - Farrar, John and Margaret, 06 Dec 1943-14 Oct 1952; 14 items (Box 10)
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1943-28 Feb 1944; 7 items (Box 10)
    - Finland, Legation of, 07 Sep 1942-08 Oct 1943; 3 items (Box 10)
    - Finletter, Thomas, 24 Jul 1950; 1 item (Box 10)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, undated; 1 item (Box 10)
    - Flanders, Ralph E., 07 Jul 1937-15 Dec 1958; 36 items (Box 10)
    - Flesch, Rudolf, 30 Jan 1956; 17 Feb 1956; 2 items (Box 10)
    - Fodor, Marcel W., 28 Jan 1923-15 Oct 1960; 71 items (Box 10)
    - Foerster, Professor F. W., 11 Nov 1941-30 Dec 1941; 10 items (Box 11)
    - Forrestal, James, 05 Apr 1946; 19 Feb 1948; 2 items (Box 11)
    - Forster, E. M., 11 Jul 1930; 1 item (Box 11)
    - Fotitch, Constantin, 24 Dec 1945-07 Mar 1946; 8 items (Box 11)
    - Frank, Jerome, 23 Apr 1938-13 Feb 1941; 20 items (Box 11)
    - Frankfurter, Felix (folder missing as of 5/25/06), 10 Apr 1936; 28 Aug 1947; 2 items (Box 11)
    - Freedom House, Inc., 06 Mar 1944-04 Feb 1948; George Field; 4 items (Box 11)
    - Free German Committee, Aug/Sep, 1943-01 Jun 1945; New York; 60 items (Box 11)
    - Freytag, Paul F., 18 Sep 1956-06 May 1960; 10 items (Box 11)
    - Fueloep-Miller, René, 23 Dec 1949-06 Sep 1960; 23 items (Box 11)
    - Fulbright, J. William, 20 Feb 1943-08 Aug 1957; 9 items (Box 11)
    - Fuller, Peta J., 13 Nov 1950-07 Apr 1959; 21 items (Box 11)
  - G - General correspondence
    - Gae-Gis, 15 May 1928-10 May 1960; 78 items (Box 11)
    - Git-Gra, 23 Nov 1937-08 Dec 1959; 55 items (Box 12)
    - Gre-Gus, 21 Oct 1943-27 Apr 1960; 47 items (Box 12)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 10 Mar 1943; 18 Jan 1944; 2 items (Box 12)
    - Gallup, George, 11 Sep 1958; 1 item (Box 12)
    - Galsworthy, John, 04 Sep 1930; 1 item (Box 12)
    - Gibson, Hugh, 27 Jan 1943-05 Jul 1949; 3 items (Box 12)
    - Gildersleeve, Virginia, 12 Mar 1948-21 Aug 1958; 8 items (Box 12)
    - Gould, Bruce and Beatrice
      - 09 Oct 1940-27 Dec 1948, 30 items (Box 12)
      - 06 Jan 1949-03 Nov 1952, 93 items (Box 12)
      - 07 Jan 1953-16 Jan 1961, 176 items (Box 12)
    - Grady, Lucretia, 04 Aug 1949-16 Feb 1955; 10 items (Box 12)
    - Graubard, Stephen, 29 Nov 1953-20 Jun 1959; 38 items (Box 13)
    - Grimm, Peter, 12 Aug 1943-07 Dec 1960; 22 items (Box 13)
    - Gromyko, Andrei, 30 Mar 1944; 1 item (Box 13)
    - Grynszpan, Herschell, 26 Jan 1939-14 May 1947; 5 items (Box 13)
    - Guaranty Trust Company, 16 Jul 1928-20 Dec 1957; 91 items (Box 13)
    - Gunther, John and Jane, 08 Dec 1938-02 Nov 1960; 26 items (Box 13)
  - H - General correspondence
    - Hab-Hau, 07 Jul 1928-16 Dec 1957; 102 items (Box 13)
    - Hav-Hil, 10 Nov 1930-06 Dec 1960; 57 items (Box 13)
    - Hin-Hyd, 04 Nov 1929-21 Nov 1958; 86 items (Box 13)
    - Halifax, Edward, 08 Mar 1942-06 Mar 1946; 3 items (Box 13)
    - Harvard University, 31 Oct 1945-02 Dec 1954; 3 items (Box 13)
    - Haterius, Evodia, 12 May 1945-11 Jan 1960; 12 items (Box 13)
    - Heil, Walter and Katherine, 23 Jan 1947-05 Jan 1960; 9 items (Box 13)
    - Hemingway, Ernest (Missing 04/2000), undated; 1 item (Box 13)
    - Hibbs, Benjamin, 05 Jan 1949-03 Jan 1951; 10 items (Box 14)
    - Hicks, Granville, 31 May 1947; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Hill, Lister, 05 Feb 1949; 2 items (Box 14)
    - Hocking, William Ernest, 23 Apr 1949-17 Dec 1959; 6 items (Box 14)
    - Holy Land Christian Committee, 22 Dec 1949-12 Nov 1951; 34 items (Box 14)
    - Hoople, Ruth, 17 Aug 1928-26 Mar 1960; 21 items (Box 14)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 01 Jan 1938-30 Dec 1958; 9 items (Box 14)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 08 May 1936-16 Dec 1958; 8 items (Box 14)
    - Houghton-Mifflin and Company, 13 Aug 1942-31 Oct 1960; 40 items (Box 14)
    - Hull, Cordell, 23 Nov 1938-26 Apr 1949; 4 items (Box 14)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 24 Mar 1954-04 Mar 1957; 4 items (Box 14)
    - Hussein, Ahmed, 18 Jul 1957-22 Apr 1958; 3 items (Box 14)
  - I - General correspondence
    - I, 09 Nov 1940-22 Jan 1958; 51 items (Box 14)
    - Incze, Lewis L., 10 Jan 1948-02 Dec 1949; 17 items (Box 14)
    - Invitations to speak, 09 Sep 1958-12 Oct 1960; 55 items (Box 14)
    - Irwin, Wallace and Tish, 29 Dec 1930-13 Apr 1959; 35 items (Box 14)
    - Ismay, Hastings Lionel, 05 Nov 1952; 1 item (Box 14)
  - J - General correspondence
    - J, 01 May 1928-14 Sep 1960; 60 items (Box 14)
    - Jewish question, 26 Apr 1933-14 Apr 1960; 37 items (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Louis, 15 May 1950; 1 item (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Margot, 28 Nov 1945-13 Oct 1960; 46 items (Box 15)
    - Johnson and Higgins, insurance brokers, 20 Jul 1953-21 Feb 1958; 46 items (Box 15)
    - Jung, Carl, 23 Sep 1949; 2 items (Box 15)
  - K - General correspondence
    - Kah-Key, 01 Jan 1928-28 Nov 1957; 62 items (Box 15)
    - Kha-Kut, 27 Jul 1926-29 Sep 1960; 96 items (Box 15)
    - Kaltenborn, H. V., 08 Aug 1942-19 Jul 1960; 13 items (Box 15)
    - Katyn Massacre Committee
      - 01 Aug 1949-07 Nov 1951, 31 items (Box 15)
      - Organizational material, 32 items (Box 15)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 17 Sep 1958-01 Oct 1958; 2 items (Box 16)
    - Keller, Father James, 03 Jan 1956; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Kellogg, Frank B., 04 Dec 1930; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Kennedy, John F., 02 Jul 1957-23 Jul 1957; 2 items (Box 16)
    - Kenny, Nick, 05 Apr 1950; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Kerr, Robert S., 16 Jul 1944; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Kiep, Hildegard, 14 May 1928-24 Sep 1949; 7 items (Box 16)
    - Kirwin, Harry and Margaret, 09 Oct 1949-06 Mar 1958; 18 items (Box 16)
    - Knickerbocker, H. R., 24 Apr 1928-28 Jun 1930; 4 items (Box 16)
    - Knox, Frank, 20 Feb 1942; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Kortner, Fritz, 30 Mar 1938-04 Sep 1941; 33 items (Box 16)
    - Koussevitzky, Serge, 21 Aug 1940-29 Aug 1944; 2 items (Box 16)
  - L - General correspondence
    - Laf-Led, 03 Mar 1938-14 Feb 1960; 50 items (Box 16)
    - Lee-Lip, 28 May 1928-07 Apr 1960; 56 items (Box 16)
    - Lit-Lyo, 11 Oct 1939-23 Jun 1959; 54 items (Box 16)
    - Landon, Alf, 12 Jan 1938-09 Mar 1960; 5 items (Box 16)
    - Lane, Arthur Bliss, 01 Mar 1949-08 Feb 1956; 6 items (Box 16)
    - Lane, Rose Wilder, 25 Jan 1927-25 Sep 1960; 29 items (Box 16)
    - Laski, Victor, undated; 4 items (Box 16)
    - Laws, Bolitha J., 04 Sep 1953-24 Apr 1958; 6 items (Box 16)
    - Le Corbusier, Charles Edoward, 27 Jun 1945; 1 item (Box 16)
    - Lecture agents
      - 15 Jan 1954-13 Aug 1956, W. Colston Leigh; 51 items (Box 16)
      - 15 Nov 1948-10 Dec 1951, Harold R. Peat and Grace Sims Peat; 102 items (Box 17)
      - 16 Jan 1952-11 Oct 1960, Harold R. Peat and Grace Sims Peat; 51 items (Box 17)
    - Lenski, Lois, 07 Sep 1947; 1 item (Box 17)
    - Lent and Abrams, 17 Jul 1957-14 Oct 1958; 13 items (Box 17)
    - Lerner, Max, 01 Mar 1956; 1 item (Box 17)
    - Lewis, John L., 12 Apr 1947-07 Jul 1947; 3 items (Box 17)
    - Lewis, Claude and Helen, 14 Jan 1951-09 Dec 1960; 9 items (Box 17)
    - Lilienthal, Alfred, 25 Aug 1949-04 Jun 1957; Holy Land Emergency Liason Program; 62 items (Box 17)
    - Lindsay, Vachel, 22 Oct 1931; 1 item (Box 17)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 14 Mar 1945-19 Feb 1960; 22 items (Box 17)
    - Listen, Hans, 10 Jan 1942-25 Jan 1943; fan mail; 75 items (Box 17)
    - Littell, Norman M.
      - 27 Nov 1944-29 Dec 1954, 79 items (Box 17)
      - 10 Jan 1955-24 Aug 1956, 29 items (Box 18)
      - 12 Jan 1957-01 Nov 1960, 13 items (Box 18)
    - Literary permissions
      - 04 Jan 1949-29 Dec 1952, and Reprints; 95 items (Box 18)
      - 05 Jan 1953-21 Dec 1955, and Reprints; 83 items (Box 18)
      - 11 Jan 1956-15 Sep 1960, and Reprints; 88 items (Box 18)
    - Lochner, Louis P., 08 Jul 1943-04 Jun 1950; 8 items (Box 18)
    - Loeb, William, 11 Apr 1947-24 Sep 1957; 61 items (Box 18)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 08 Nov 1949-27 Mar 1953; 4 items (Box 18)
    - Lovett, Robert A., 15 Dec 1947-15 Apr 1948; 6 items (Box 19)
    - Lowell, Ross H., 13 Feb 1945-20 May 1947; 28 items (Box 19)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 22 Oct 1940-24 Sep 1952; 14 items (Box 19)
    - Luce, Henry R., 12 Mar 1948-10 Nov 1954; 6 items (Box 19)
    - Luchaire, Antonia Valentina, Jan, 1939-11 Oct 1941; 16 items (Box 19)
    - Lyons, Leonard, 05 Dec 1944-24 Feb 1950; 4 items (Box 19)
  - M - General correspondence
    - Mac-May, 31 Mar 1938-28 Jan 1961; 105 items (Box 19)
    - McA-Mid, 17 Dec 1922-27 Jun 1960; 98 items (Box 19)
    - Mil-Myl, 06 Mar 1931-04 Feb 1960; 115 items (Box 19)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 04 Feb 1955; 1 item (Box 19)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 02 Jun 1942-22 Jun 1942; 2 items (Box 19)
    - Manhattan Publishing Company, 23 Oct 1959-08 Nov 1960; 24 items (Box 19)
    - Mann, Thomas, 21 Apr 1937-15 Apr 1941; 17 items (Box 19)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 11 Jan 1943-07 Apr 1943; 2 items (Box 20)
    - Marlboro College
      - 18 Dec 1946-14 Nov 1950, 38 items (Box 20)
      - 06 Jan 1951-21 Nov 1955, 31 items (Box 20)
    - Marshall, Gen. George, 27 Feb 1942-26 Mar 1948; 4 items (Box 20)
    - Masaryk, Jan, 15 Nov 1947-24 Mar 1948; 5 items (Box 20)
    - Mathews, William R., 09 Jan 1942-29 Jul 1958; 45 items (Box 20)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, 30 May 1923; 1 item (Box 20)
    - Maxwell, Elsa, 03 Jan 1950; 1 item (Box 20)
    - McMahon, Sen. Brien, 28 Sep 1949-14 Dec 1950; 2 items (Box 20)
    - Meneken, H. L., 25 Mar 1926-12 Dec 1955; 39 items (Box 20)
    - Menjou, Aldolphe, 21 Aug 1933; 1 item (Box 20)
    - Menuhin, Yehudi, 23 Oct 1959; 1 item (Box 20)
    - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 01 Feb 1944; 1 item (Box 20)
    - Model, Roland and Stone, 13 Nov 1950-09 Sep 1958; Stockbrokers; 22 items (Box 20)
    - Montgomery, John Flournoy, 20 Feb 1950-10 May 1954; 34 items (Box 20)
    - Morrow, Edward R., 04 Jan 1954 (Box 20)
    - Morse, John and Martha, 19 Mar 1951-22 Oct 1959; 35 items (Box 20)
    - Moses, John, 09 Aug 1937-05 Aug 1960; 58 items (Box 20)
    - Moses, Robert, 11 Feb 1944; 1 item (Box 20)
    - Montgelas, Albrecht, 30 Sep 1940-22 Nov 1946; 17 items (Box 20)
    - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel, 17 Nov 1938-03 Jan 1954; 26 items (Box 20)
    - Mundt, Karl, 19 May 1941-21 Dec 1948; 4 items (Box 20)
    - Muste, A. J., 27 Mar 1948-31 Mar 1954; 10 items (Box 20)
  - N - General correspondence
    - Nag-Nea, 20 Oct 1927-19 Feb 1958; 76 items (Box 21)
    - Nea-New York E, 03 Nov 1927-22 Jul 1960; 45 items (Box 21)
    - New York N-Nich, 18 Dec 1938-27 Aug 1958; 47 items (Box 21)
    - Nic-Not, 08 Dec 1941-28 Apr 1960; 39 items (Box 21)
    - Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 14 Feb 1958; 1 item (Box 21)
    - National Council for Prevention of War, 06 Nov 1945-27 Sep 1952; 8 items (Box 21)
    - National Council for Youth, 17 Mar 1954-03 Sep 1957; 52 items (Box 21)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 30 Dec 1949-17 Dec 1954; 26 items (Box 21)
    - New York Post, 03 Apr 1936-01 Oct 1952; 48 items (Box 21)
    - Newspaper Guild of New York, 07 Jan 1941-02 Jan 1948; 17 items (Box 21)
    - Newton, Caroline, 14 Oct 1930-07 Jun 1960; 49 items (Box 21)
    - Ngo-Dinh-Diem, undated; 4 items (Box 22)
    - Nichols, William, 28 Jan 1949-28 Jun 1955; 6 items (Box 22)
    - Nicholson, Harold, 11 Jul 1938-29 Aug 1939; 4 items (Box 22)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 18 May 1951; 2 items (Box 22)
    - Nizer, Louis, 09 Jan 1940-13 Apr 1950; 51 items (Box 22)
  - O - General correspondence
    - O, 01 Jul 1931-Nov 1960; 43 items (Box 22)
    - "On the Record", 08 Aug 1958-18 Sep 1958; fan mail-discontinuation of column; 96 items (Box 22)
    - Once on Christmas, 12 Dec 1946-30 May 1958; 26 items (Box 22)
    - Ormerod, William, 26 Mar 1943-27 Jan 1958; British Information Services; 82 items (Box 22)
  - P - General correspondence
    - Pag-Per, 27 Apr 1945-25 Jun 1959; 60 items (Box 22)
    - Pfa-Por, 06 Jul 1931-05 Dec 1959; 43 items (Box 22)
    - Pos-Pye, 21 Oct 1927-25 May 1958; 40 items (Box 23)
    - Paderewski, Ignace, 10 Jan 1941; 1 item (Box 23)
    - Panel of Americans, 03 Sep 1953-23 Apr 1957; 22 items (Box 23)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 02 Nov 1940; 1 item (Box 23)
    - Parsons, Clementine M., 28 Sep 1960-25 Jan 1961; 9 items (Box 23)
    - Patterson, Grove, 08 Nov 1948-25 Jul 1955; 11 items (Box 23)
    - Pearsall, Richard, 21 Dec 1954-23 May 1958; 11 items (Box 23)
    - Pegler, Westbrook, 17 Nov 1938-19 Nov 1938; 4 items (Box 23)
    - Perkins, Frances, 12 Nov 1930-03 Apr 1947; 2 items (Box 23)
    - Pickford, Mary, 20 May 1941; 1 item (Box 23)
    - Pierce, Loren Ray, 19 Sep 1940-07 Oct 1949; 43 items (Box 23)
    - Porter, Sylvia, 16 Dec 1954; 1 item (Box 23)
    - Powell, George M., 16 Nov 1938-08 Jan 1951; 51 items (Box 23)
    - Praeger, Frederick A., Inc., 1959-05 Dec 1960; 10 items (Box 23)
    - Publication permissions, Germany, 10 May 1949-18 Oct 1956; 36 items (Box 23)
    - Pulitzer, Joseph, 01 Nov 1939; 1 item (Box 23)
  - R - General correspondence
    - Rab-Rav, 08 Jul 1931-01 Nov 1960; 55 items (Box 23)
    - Raw-Ree, 27 Jan 1942-17 Dec 1958; 45 items (Box 23)
    - Ref-Ric, 15 Jan 1932-01 Apr 1960; 63 items (Box 23)
    - Rid-Rut, Jun, 1928-17 Nov 1960; 109 items (Box 24)
    - Reader's Digest, 03 Sep 1958-08 Nov 1959; fan mail; 67 items (Box 24)
    - Henry Regnery Company, 16 Apr 1951-07 Dec 1959; 16 items (Box 24)
    - Reinheimer, Howard, 03 Jun 1939-09 Jul 1941; 24 items (Box 24)
    - Requests-to contribute articles and information, 27 Dec 1958-15 Aug 1960; 21 items (Box 24)
    - Requests-speaking, 02 Dec 1953-29 Aug 1958; 62 items (Box 24)
    - Requests-miscellaneous, 25 Oct 1954-02 Jun 1958; 66 items (Box 24)